Guide to the Corcoran Gallery of Art and Corcoran College of Art + Design, Corcoran Gallery of Art Board of Trustees records, 1869-2012 COR0001.0.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Records transferred post-1980, 1953-2012; 1979-2008; Series 2
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes [2/2], 1976-1977; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes [1/2], 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes [2/2], 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes [1/2], 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Excutive Committee meeting minutes [2/2], 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Board of Trustees - Oct Meeting, 1969 October; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Quarterly Meeting, 1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Board of Govenors, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Cabbages + Kings, 1969-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - "Administrative", Undated; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Niles Bond, 1970-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - CGA-Misc (1 of 2), Undated; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - CGA-Misc (2 of 2), Undated; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - State of Building, 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Archives, 1981; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Planning Projections, 1968; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Corcoran Committee, 1970-1972; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Organization, 1969-1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Extra Copies, Crafts, Etc, 1970-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Women's Committee, 1965-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Acquisition Policy etc., 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - National Committee, 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Administrative Directives, 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Joint Executive Committee, 1975; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Art School, 1970-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Board of Govenors (Candidates), 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Governors Misc., 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Niles Bond, 1969; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Mr. Aldus Chapin, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - School Budget, 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Case Statement Corcoran Gallery W. Hopps, 1970; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Executive Committee, 1970-1979; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Executive Committee, 1976-1977; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Joint Executive Committee, 1970-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Govenors Minutes, 1970-1971; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Works of Art Meetings' Lists, 1967-1973; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Executive Committee Meetings Information, Agendas, Minutes, 1976; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Executive Committee, 1980; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Board of Trustees, 1980-1981; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Committee Minutes, 1980-1981; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes Vol. 5, 1971 January 25 - 1971 March 5; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1976, Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1978-1979, Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1973, Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1974, Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees (1 of 2), 1976-1981; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees (1 of 2), 1976-1981; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Trustee Records By-Laws-Various, 1970; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting, 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Trustee Reports, 1975-1977; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, 1970-1979; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees, 1970-1979; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees: Meeting Minutes Fall, 1976; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees Committee Meetings, 1976; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 11, 1975 October 6 - 1976 July 26; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 10 [1/2], 1973 April 4 - 1975 August 6; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 10 [2/2], 1973 April 4 - 1975 August 6; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 12, 1976 September 27 - 1977 July 25; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 13 [1/2], 1977 September 26 - 1978 July 31; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 13 [2/2], 1977 September 26 - 1978 July 31; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 14 [1/2], 1978 September 25 - 1979 July 30; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes Vol. 14 [2/2], 1978 September 25 - 1979 July 30; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes [1/3], 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes [2/3], 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes [3/3], 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes [1/2], 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Board of Trustee Meeting Minutes [2/2], 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1980 January 28; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1980 March 24; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1980 May 23; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1980 July 28; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1980 September 22; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Full Board Trustee Meeting, 1980 November 24; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1981 January 26; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1981 March 23; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1981 May 18; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1981 July 27; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1981 September 28; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1981 November 23; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1982 January 25; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1982 March 22; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1982 May 24; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Full Board Meeting, 1982 July 26; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 February 11; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 March 14; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 April 14; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Executive Board Meeting, 1980 May 12; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 June 9; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 July 14; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 August 11; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 September 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 October 20; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 November 10; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980 December 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 January 12; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 February 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 March 9; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 April 20; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 May 11; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 June 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 July 13; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 August 13; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 September 14; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Special Meeting Executive Committee Architect for Proposed Corcoran Annex, 1981 September 18; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 October 19; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 November 9; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1981 December 14; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 January 11; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 February 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Special Meeting of Executive Committee Bldgs/Grnds, 1982 March 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 March 8; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 April 12; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 May 10; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 June 14; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 July 12; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1982; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1982 August 9; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - School Development Committee, 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Building and Grounds Committee, 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - Investment Finance Committee, 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Development Committee, 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Board of Trustees, 1983; Series 2 (Box 26A, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1982; Series 2 (Box 26A, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee, 1983; Series 2 (Box 26A, Folder 3)
  - Senior Staff Meeting, 1983; Series 2 (Box 26B, Folder 1)
  - Works of Art Committee, 1982; Series 2 (Box 26B)
  - Works of Art Committee, 1983; Series 2 (Box 26B)
  - Board of Trustees FY91 Minutes, Board of Trustees list, Board of Trustees by laws, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Exec. Comm. Minutes 1991 - 1992 (1 of 3), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Exec. Comm. Minutes 1991 - 1992 (2 of 3), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Exec. Comm. Minutes 1991 - 1992 (3 of 3), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1991 August 8; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1991 September 16, 1991 November 18; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1991 March 25, 1991 May 20; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1991 January 28; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees 1993-1994 (1 of 4), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees 1993-1994 (2 of 4), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees 1993-1994 (3 of 4), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees 1993-1994 (4 of 4), Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [1/3], Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [2/3], Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [3/3], Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [1/4], 1995; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 (1 of 4), 1995; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [2/4], 1995; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [3/4], 1995; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Board of Trustees Exec. Minutes 1994 [4/4], 1995; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [1/4], 1996; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [2/4], 1996; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [3/4], 1996; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [4/4], 1996; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [1/4], 1997; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [2/4], 1997; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [3/4], 1997; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [4/4], 1997; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [1/2], 1998; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [2/2], 1998; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes ([1/3], 1999; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [2/3], 1999; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [3/3], 1999; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [1/2], 2000; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Comm. Minutes [2/2], 2000; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Finance Investement Managements Committees, 1997 November - 1999 January; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 2001; Series 2 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Background material [1/4], 2009-2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Background material [2/4], 2011-2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Background material [3/4], 2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Background material [4/4], 2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Cocoran futures [1/4], 2012 January 20; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Cocoran futures [2/4], 2012 January 20; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Corcoran futures [3/4], 2012 January 20; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Corcoran futures [4/4], 2012 January 20; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Corcoran futures finance data [1/2], 2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Corcoran futures finance data [2/2], 2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Corcoran futures advance information, 2012 April; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes and resolutions, 2010; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes and resolutions, 2011; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes and resolutions, 2012; Series 2 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Director's Office Search, 1990; Series 2 (Box R1, Folder 1)
  - Director's Search, 1990; Series 2 (Box R1, Folder 2)
  - Management Consultants for the Arts, Inc., 1990; Series 2 (Box R1, Folder 3)
  - Director Search records [1/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R1, Folder 4)
  - Director Search records 2/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R1, Folder 5)
  - Director Search records [3/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R2, Folder 1)
  - Director Search records [4/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R2, Folder 2)
  - Director Search records [5/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R2, Folder 3)
  - Director Search records [6/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R2, Folder 4)
  - Director Search records [7/7], 1990; Series 2 (Box R2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 2005; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 2005-2006; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 2005-2007; Series 2 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Early meeting ledgers, 1869-1952; Series 3
  This series is arranged chronologically and by ledger type.
  This series contains Meeting Minutes and Reports of the Board of Trustees in bound ledgers from 1869-1952. The ledgers also contain indexes of the contents of the reports.
  Records of the Board of Trustees Meetings within this series are also located in individual report files in Series 1 Early meeting records, 1869-1980.
  - Secretary's Record, 1869 May 15-1879 October 20; Series 3 (Flat box 2, Ledger 1)
    Pages crossed out at earlier date, information transferred to Board Minutes in Journal of Official Proceedings of The Trustees of The Corcoran Gallery of Art.
  - Index to Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of The Corcoran Gallery of Art, Vol. 1, 1869 May 15-1888 December 3; Series 3 (Flat box 2, Ledger 2)
  - Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Vol. 1, 1869 May 15-1888 December 3; Series 3 (Box 31, Volume 1)
    Containing final form of Board Minutes, and Commitee reports from Jan. 8, 1883.
  - Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Vol. 2 (indexed), 1889 Jan. 14- 1898 Dec. 12; Series 3 (Box 32, Volume 1)
    Containing final form of Board Minutes, and Commitee reports
  - Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Vol. 3 (indexed), 1899 Jan. 17-1909 Jan. 15; Series 3 (Box 33, Volume 1)
    Containing final form of Board Minutes. Committee Reports discontinued after June 18, 1906.
  - Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Vol. 4 (indexed), 1909 Jan. 18-1926 Dec. 19; Series 3 (Box 33, Volume 2)
    Journal discontinued; Minutes typed hereafter.
  - Official Proceedings of Committees of The Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1874 Jan. 26-1886 May 30; Series 3 (Box 34, Volume 1)
    Including Curator's Annual Reports.
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, Vol. I, 1882 January 9-1889 November 27 (Flat box 3, Ledger 1)
    Crossed out at an earlier date and information transferred to the Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art.
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, Vol. II, 1890 January 13-1900 June 26; Series 3 (Flat box 3, Ledger 2)
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, Vol. III, 1900 October 15-1909 January 15; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Ledger 1)
    Hand and typewritten. Crossed out and transferred to the Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of The Corcoran Gallery of Art.
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, Vol. V, 1916 November 2 1916-1922 January 16; Series 3 (Flat box 6, Ledger 1)
    Typed. Crossed out at an earlier date and information transferred to the Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art.
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, Vol. VII (indexed), 1927 January 17-1934 December 7; Series 3 (Flat box 9, Ledger 1)
    This now takes the place of the Journal of the Official Proceedings of the Corcoran Gallery of Art. (Typed)
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, Vol. VIII, 1935 January 21-1945 October 19; Series 3 (Flat box 11, Ledger 1)
  - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Trustees, 1946 February 1-1952 October 15; Series 3 (Flat box 13, Ledger 1)